Guide to the Carl Feiss papers, [ca.1928]-1991
Feiss, Carl papers, [ca.1928]-1991
- Series II. Professional Papers
  - Projects, Reference Materials
    - Miscellaneous Personal Papers: including correspondence., 1968-1977 (Box 58, Folder 26-27)
    - Unwin, Raymond: "Housing and Town Planning Lectures," Columbia University., 1936-1937 (Box 58, Folder 28)
  - Published Material
    - Urban Studies at the University of Florida. Gainesville, Florida: University of Florida, 1972-1975. (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Recommendations on Government Housing Policies and Programs. Washington, D.C.: President's Advisory Committee on Government Housing Policies and Programs, 1953. (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - The Region's Form and Appearance. (East Central Florida Regional Planning Council), 1965 (Box 59, Folder 3-4)
    - Historic Columbus Building Inventory, Muscogee County, Georiga., 1967 (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Historic Preservation Tomorrow. Williamsburg, Virginia: National Trust for Historic Preservation, 1967. (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - Norwich Historic Homes and Families. Stonington, Connecticut: Pequot Press, 1967. (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - An American Guidebook System for the Arts: A Prospectus., 1969 (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - Archeological Survey of Ft. Benning: Revised Draft Final Report., 1979 (Box 59, Folder 9-10)
    - Historic Preservation/Conservation Study for the Gainesville Central City Revitalization Program., 1979 (Box 59, Folder 11)
    - Central Business District Revitalization Proposals: Perry, Florida., 1977 (Box 59, Folder 12)
    - A Citizen's Guide for Historic Conservation: A Bicentennial Booklet., 1976 (Box 59, Folder 13)
    - Planning for Florida's Growth., 1976 (Box 59, Folder 14)
    - The Local Government Comprehensive Planning Act., 1975 (Box 59, Folder 15)
    - Transfer of Development Rights: A New Concept in Land Use Management., 1974 (Box 59, Folder 16)
    - Working Paper 6: Experiences of Florida in Planning for Land Use., 1974 (Box 59, Folder 17)
    - Working Paper 7: Environment and Florida Voters: Their Concerns on Growth; Energy; Pollution; Land Use Controls; In-Migration Taxes; Politics and the Future of the State., 1974 (Box 59, Folder 18)
    - Working Paper 8: Takings, Due Process and the Police Powers: An Analysis of Judicial Approaches to Land Use Regulations in Florida., 1974 (Box 59, Folder 19)
    - Symposium on Urbanization in the South., 1973 (Box 59, Folder 20)
    - Working Paper 1: Current University of Florida Urban and Regional Research in Gainesville and Alachua County. Gainesville, Florida: University of Florida, 1973. (Box 59, Folder 21)
    - Working Paper 2: Bibliography of Research and Documents Relating to Gainesville and Alachua County. Gainesville, Florida: University of Florida, 1973. (Box 59, Folder 22)
    - Working Paper 4: Migration Into Florida 1940-1973. (Box 59, Folder 23)
    - A Guide to Macon's Architectural and Historical Heritage. Macon, Georgia: Middle Georgia Historical Society, 1972. (Box 59, Folder 24)
    - A Guide to Historic Beaufort. Beaufort, South Carolina: The Beaufort Historic Foundation, 1970. (Box 59, Folder 25)
    - Five-Year Program of Operation for the Mississippi-Arkansas-Tennessee Council of Governments Summary Report., 1970 (Box 59, Folder 26)
    - Portrait of Essex. Barre, Massachusetts: Barre Publishers, 1969. (Box 59, Folder 27)
    - Testimony before the House Banking and Currency Committee Ad Hoc Subcommittee on Urban Growth., 1969 (Box 59, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence and Related Materials
    - A-General, 1972-1986 (Box 61, Folder 1-2)
    - B-General, 1977-1990 (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - C-General, 1977-1987 (Box 61, Folder 4-5)
    - Cosmos Club, 1982-1990 (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - E-General, 1975-1986 (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - Euston, Andrew, 1980-1988 (Box 61, Folder 8-9)
    - F-General, 1950-1984 (Box 61, Folder 10)
    - G-General, 1984-1989 (Box 61, Folder 11)
    - H-General, 1977-1989 (Box 61, Folder 12)
    - H-General, 1973-1978 (Box 61, Folder 13)
    - K-General, 1971-1976 (Box 61, Folder 14)
    - L-General, 1982-1987 (Box 61, Folder 15)
    - Lewis, Paul Jr.: Circle City, 1983 (Box 61, Folder 16)
    - M-General, 1975-1985 (Box 61, Folder 17-18)
    - N-General, 1973-1986 (Box 61, Folder 19)
    - P-General, 1975-1983 (Box 61, Folder 20-21)
    - S-General, 1975-1990 (Box 61, Folder 22-24)
    - W-General, 1980-1985 (Box 61, Folder 25)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1978-1988 (Box 61, Folder 26)
  - 1000 Friends of Florida
    - Murley, James: 1000 Friends of Florida, 1988 (Box 61, Folder 27)
    - Concept Paper, 1985 (Box 61, Folder 28)
    - General Material and Correspondence, 1985 (Box 61, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence, 1986-1991 (Box 61, Folder 30)
    - Board Meetings: agendas, minutes., 1986 (Box 61, Folder 31)
    - Policy Documents, 1987 (Box 61, Folder 32)
    - General Material and Correspondence, 1987 (Box 61, Folder 33)
    - General Material and Correspondence, 1988 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - General Material and Correspondence, 1989 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Plan Review Committee: 920 S. Ocean Blvd., 1988 (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - General Material and Correspondence, 1990 (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - General Material and Correspondence, 1991 (Box 62, Folder 5-6)
    - Report to Board, 1991 (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - General Material, 1992 (Box 62, Folder 8)
    - Friends of Florida, Friends of Oregon, Friends of Japan, 1987 (Box 62, Folder 9)
  - Projects, Reference Materials, Correspondence
    - U.S. Housing Legislation, 1949, 1954, 1983 (Box 62, Folder 10)
    - University of Pennsylvania, 1988 (Box 62, Folder 11-12)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1973-1981 (Box 62, Folder 13)
    - AIA Regional and Urban Design Committee: correspondence, memoranda, meeting minutes, "Revitalization of the City Center: The Impact of Regional Growth Pressures on Downtown St. Louis," "The Urbanization of Suburbia: Metropolitan Growth in the Washington Region.", 1987 (Box 62, Folder 14)
    - US/ICOMOS (United States/International Council on Monuments and Sites): correspondence., 1984-1990 (Box 62, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous materials: clippings, correspondence, photographs, Historic Columbus Foundation., 1972-1984 (Box 62, Folder 16-17)
    - Conservation Award, Department of the Interior: correspondence, clippings., 1976 (Box 62, Folder 18)
    - Mayo, Florida: Old Courthouse: clippings, correspondence., 1982-1989 (Box 62, Folder 19)
    - Gainesville, Florida: Sugarfoot Prairie: correspondence, clippings, petition, meeting agenda, The Sugarfoot Quarterly, plans., 1979-1983 (Box 62, Folder 20)
    - Gainesville, Florida: Sugarfoot Prairie: The Sugarfoot Newsletter., 1984-1985 (Box 62, Folder 21)
    - Gainesville, Florida: Historic Gainesville: correspondence, Preservation in Progress., 1972-1990 (Box 62, Folder 22)
    - UC/ICOMOS (United States/International Council of Monuments and Sites): correspondence, information packet, "World Heritage List," "International Programs to Preserve the Cultural Heritage of Mankind," meeting agenda, memoranda, newsletters., 1984-1991 (Box 62, Folder 23)
    - Florida State Division of Archives and History: correspondence, plans, "Florida Master Site File," brochure., 1972-1978 (Box 62, Folder 24)
    - Florida State University: correspondence., 1981-1988 (Box 62, Folder 25)
    - Fulbright Fellowship: correspondence., 1981-1983 (Box 62, Folder 26)
    - AIA Regional and Urban Design Committee: correspondence, list of members., 1988 (Box 62, Folder 27)
    - Gainesville, Florida: Northwest 5th Ave. Project Plans, District 1644: correspondence, budget, "General Information and Instructions for Application/Suggestion for Community Development Block Grant-Funded Activity," resolution R-82-56., 1981-1983 (Box 62, Folder 28)
    - TROPARC Architectural Archives: budget proposals, project updates, memoranda., 1985-1986 (Box 62, Folder 29)
    - APA Journal (American Planners Association): correspondence., 1984-1985 (Box 62, Folder 30)
    - U.S. Federal Preservation Legislation, 1966-1982 (Box 62, Folder 31)
    - U.S Preservation: District and Neighborhood: Landmark and Historic District Commissions, correspondence, brochures., 1976-1978 (Box 62, Folder 32)
    - Florida: Mayo: correspondence, "Downtown Beautification and Revitalization Study.", 1980 (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Florida: Orlando Sentinel: "Florida's Shame:" correspondence with Lesli Kemp, clippings., 1985 (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Florida: Jefferson County Historical Association: correspondence., 1976 (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Florida: North Central Florida Regional Planning Commission: correspondence., 1989 (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - CRM (Cultural Resources Management Information for Parks, Federal Agencies, Indian Tribes, States, Local Governments and the Private Sector), 1991 (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Florida: Historic Ocala Preservation Society: correspondence., 1986 (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - U.S. Department of Interior, National Register Guidelines: Interim guidelines, correspondence, "Historic Preservation Plan, Savannah, Georgia," "Standards for Historic Preservation Projects," "Policies and Procedures.", 1979 (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1980-1987 (Box 63, Folder 8)
    - University of Florida: College of Architecture: correspondence., 1985 (Box 63, Folder 9)
    - University of Florida Library: Rare Books correspondence, "Feiss on Florida," "World Capitals," "True or False: Living Architecture Old and New.", 1987-1988 (Box 63, Folder 10-11)
    - RFUF (Retired Faculty of the University of Florida): correspondence., 1987-1988 (Box 63, Folder 12)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: schedule of board of trustees meetings. Invitation to 40th Anniversary of the National Capital Area Chapter Celebration. Photograph of Feiss., 1976, 1987-1988 (Box 63, Folder 13)
    - RFUF (Retired Faculty of the University of Florida): Learned Scholars Institute: correspondence, memoranda, articles of incorporation., 1975-1990 (Box 63, Folder 14)
    - Cornell University Archives: correspondence., 1966-1991 (Box 63, Folder 15-16)
    - "Present at the Creation: A Personal History of ?With Heritage So Rich.'", 1981 (Box 63, Folder 17)
    - Clippings: Preservation News., 1949 (Box 63, Folder 18)
    - National Trust Honor Award: certificate, ribbons, correspondence, photographs., 1981 (Box 63, Folder 19)
    - Transcript of Feiss's personal narrative., 1970 (Box 63, Folder 20)
    - Retirement correspondence, 1981 (Box 63, Folder 21)
    - German Trip: correspondence, film negatives, photographs, travel log., 1937 (Box 63, Folder 22)
    - Transcript of interview of Feiss and related correspondence., 1991 (Box 63, Folder 23)
    - Photos of structures, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 24)
    - Personal correspondence, list of party invitees, 1935-1990 (Box 63, Folder 25)
  - Conferences and Meetings
    - [American Civilization Seminar:] correspondence re: Faculty Club of the University of Florida, letter of recommendation for Maria Zifou, correspondence re: Friends of Florida, calendar, photograph., 1981-1987 (Box 64, Folder 27)
    - Cranbrook Academy of Art: correspondence, interview with Feiss, invitation, Cranbrook Quarterly., 1980-1985 (Box 64, Folder 28)
    - Columbia University: 50th Anniversary Commemoration of the Graduate Program in Urban Planning: program, copy of certificate of appreciation, 1987 (Box 64, Folder 29)
    - Denver University: greeting card, correspondence, Symposia, memoranda., 1981 (Box 64, Folder 30)
    - Livable Cities Conference: correspondence, clippings, program, membership roster., 1983-1989 (Box 64, Folder 31)
    - National Trust for Historical Preservation: San Francisco, California, October 16-20, 1991: correspondence, expense form, program, educational session descriptions, list of honorees, Historic Preservation Forum. (Box 64, Folder 32)
    - New Orleans: "Selling the City without Selling Out: The Challenge of Tourism Management," correspondence., 1988 (Box 64, Folder 33)
    - Remaking Cities Conference: Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, March 2-5, 1988: program, correspondence, Columns (Box 64, Folder 34)
    - Richmond Conference: Richmond, Virginia, November 7-10, 1991: correspondence, Planning History Present. (Box 64, Folder 35)
  - Oversize Material
    - Awards, certificates, reproduction of a sketch of Feiss, degrees, "Charleston, South Carolina: Historic Preservation Plan.", 1938-1990 (Box 65)
    - "Charleston, South Carolina: Historic Preservation Plan.", c. 1973 (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Street Elevation Plans for unnamed project (Street names include Bay, State, and Concord), Undated (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Edison Voicewriter Diamond Disks
    - AIA Report, Urban America Report, Letters, Wasteland, Art and the Wasteland. (Box 63, Folder 30)
    - Speech at AIA New Communities Conference, November 3-6, 1971. (Box 63, Folder 31)
    - Grand Rapids., 1970 (Box 63, Folder 32)
    - AIA Testimony: H.R. 16647, July 10, 1970. (Box 63, Folder 33)
    - TVA Report (Tennessee Valley Authority): June 3, 1969., 1970 (Box 63, Folder 34)
    - Cranbrook: March 28, 1969. (Box 63, Folder 35)
    - National Conference on Urban Problems: April 1968. (Box 63, Folder 36)
    - Blackman, Dorothy: materials related to Hamilton County Courthouse., 1984 (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - CARIMOS (Caribbean Monuments and Sites): meeting schedule, "The Architectural Archive of the Greater Caribbean," correspondence, brochures, National Endowment for the Arts Cover Sheet., 1985-1987 (Box 64, Folder 2-4)
    - Cranbrook: correspondence, clippings., 1982 (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - Columbia University: correspondence., 1940-1949 (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - Denver: clippings, correspondence re: University of Denver, inaugural ceremonies., 1942-1950 (Box 64, Folder 7-8)
    - England and Italy: correspondence., 1973-1989 (Box 64, Folder 9)
    - Florida Defenders of the Environment: correspondence, brochures, The Monitor., 1972-1984 (Box 64, Folder 10)
    - Florida: Jacksonville Community Council: correspondence, clippings., 1984 (Box 64, Folder 11)
    - Florida: Mayo: correspondence., 1983 (Box 64, Folder 12)
    - Moore, Alexander: correspondence, including "The Metropolitan Shopping Mall: Positive Nodes in the Conurbation," "Walt Disney World: Bounded Ritual Space and the Playful Pilgrimage Center.", 1981 (Box 64, Folder 13)
    - National League of Cities, Urban Environmental Design Project: correspondence, clippings, brochure, program for 1st National Conference: "Design: the Key to Building Cities.", 1980-1981 (Box 64, Folder 14)
    - Political: correspondence, clippings, flyers, photographs., 1981-1985 (Box 64, Folder 15)
    - Pratt, J. MacDougall: correspondence., 1982 (Box 64, Folder 16)
    - Saarinen: notes, clippings, "El Iel Saarinen: The Architect as Planner.", 1982-1984 (Box 64, Folder 17)
    - Seibert, Edward J.: photographs., n.d. (Box 64, Folder 18)
    - State Historic Preservation Officers: correspondence, photographs, notes, list of officers, "With Heritage So Rich.", 1981 (Box 64, Folder 19)
    - Tennessee Valley Authority: "The Unified Development of the Tennessee River System," "The Spatial Structure of Economic Development in the Tennessee Valley.", 1936, 1955 (Box 64, Folder 20)
    - Tennessee Valley Authority: Annual Report of the Tennessee Valley Authority., 1967 (Box 64, Folder 21)
    - Tennessee Valley Authority: Gober Work File: correspondence., 1988 (Box 64, Folder 22)
    - United Nations Center for Human Settlements International Shelter for the Homeless, 1983-1984 (Box 64, Folder 23)
    - Unwin memorabilia: correspondence., 1988-1989 (Box 64, Folder 24)
    - Clippings, 1936-1939 (Box 64, Folder 25)
    - University of Florida: correspondence, memoranda, course notes, photographs., 1984-1986 (Box 64, Folder 26)
  - Audio cassettes
    - "New Towns" by Carl Feiss, November 17-19, 1980., TR-10846-10849 (Box 64)
    - "Contemporary Local Planning in the United States" by Carl Feiss, November 26, 1980., TR-10850 (Box 64)
    - "Planning Problems" by Carl Feiss, December 1, 1980., TR-10851 (Box 64)
    - "Maria and Imageability Interview" with Carl Feiss, December 3, 1980., TR-10852 (Box 64)